RG 005:033, Office of the Governor: Abraham Ribicoff (1955-1961)
Connecticut State Library
Abraham Ribicoff records
1955-1961
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Governor (1955-1961: Ribicoff)
111 cubic feet
Gov. Ribicoff's correspondence, subject files, flood of 1955 files, highway safety files, 1958 campaign files, appointment files, speeches, media articles, and press files.
RG005_033
T001281
Biographical Note
Born: April 9, 1910, New Britain, Connecticut.
College: University of Chicago, 1933.
Political Party: Democrat.
Offices: U.S. Congress, 1949-1953; Governor of Connecticut, 1951-1955; US Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1961-1962; U.S. Senate, 1963-1981.
Died: February 22, 1998, New York City.
Connecticut's Democratic Party of Connecticut, under the guidance of its chairman John Bailey, did what seemed impossible in the "Land of Steady Habits". It got a Jewish candidate elected governor. Abraham Ribicoff of New Britain became a lawyer in 1933 and opened his practice in Hartford where he became friends with Bailey. In 1938 Ribicoff was elected to the General Assembly. He also was a judge in Hartford's Municipal Court for 1945-47. He married Ruth Siegel in 1931 and they had two children. After her death in 1972 he married Lois Mathes.
One of the aspects that Bailey liked about Ribicoff was his ability to project a good image as a candidate. Elected to the U.S. congress for 1949-53, Ribicoff ran for the U.S. Senate in 1952 and lost. However, in the Republican landslide that year he ran an extremely close race. Convinced that he was the party's best candidate for governor, Bailey promoted him for the position in the 1954 elections. Future president, John F. Kennedy, gave the party's keynote address at its state convention. Ribicoff's clean-cut and dignified appearance helped offset some hidden anti-Semitic campaigning against him. His "American Dream" speech also helped convince voters that everyone in the state had the right to seek elective office. His personal appeal with the voters is evident in that he became the only Democrat to gain state office that year. Ribicoff won reelection in 1958.
As governor, Ribicoff promoted a moderate program for the state that sought compromise rather than confrontation with the General Assembly. Among his accomplishments were more aid to patients in state institutions, more highway construction, the creation of an adult probation system, and a bonus for Korean War veterans. He also called the legislature into special session to consider a law that would provide for primary elections in the state. One of the challenges to his administration came in 1955 when two hurricanes caused enormous damage in the state. Ribicoff called a special session of the legislature to develop programs of relief for Connecticut's citizens. During his second term he worked with a Republican legislature and used his veto powers to maintain the state's budget without raising taxes. The process to eliminate the county government system was begun at this time and both state government and the courts underwent reorganization. State bussing for Parochial and private schools was passed under his leadership. One innovation Ribicoff used while governor was in holding daily press conferences. If he could not answer a reporter's question he would call a state agency during the conference to find the answer.
Ribicoff and Bailey were among the earliest supporters of John F. Kennedy for U.S. President. When Kennedy was elected in 1960 he appointed Ribicoff to his cabinet as Secretary of Health, Education and Welfare. Although Ribicoff resigned as governor in 1961 to work in Washington, he was back in Connecticut in 1962. He had become frustrated with the way Congress hindered the operation of his agency's programs and decided to return to Connecticut and run for the U.S. Senate. He won this election and served in the Senate from 1963 until he retired to Connecticut in 1981. The house that he lived in when he became governor in 1955 still stands in Hartford and it is privately owned. The U.S. Government building on Main Street, Hartford is named in his honor.
Bibliography
Citizens Look at Congress 1972
Congressional Quarterly's Guide to United States Elections. Washington, D.C.: Congressional Quarterly, 1994 [CSL call number GIS Ref JK 1967 .C662 1994.
Glashan, Roy R. American Governors and Gubernatorial Elections, 1775-1975. Stillwater, Minn.: Croixside Press, 1975 [CSL call number JK 2447 .G53 1975].
Janick, Herbert F. A Diverse People: Connecticut, 1914 to the Present. Chester, Conn.: Pequot Press, c1975 [CSL call number HistRef Conn Doc St22eacs v. 5].
Lieberman, Joseph. The Legacy, Connecticut Politics, 1930-1980 Hartford, Conn.: Spoonwood Press, 1981 [CSL call number JK 3395 .L53 1981].
Payne, Carol Abraham A. Ribicoff: Democratic Senator from Connecticut, written for Ralph Nader Congress project, Washington, D.C.: Grossman, 1972 [CSL call number E 840 .R5 R3].
Snyder, Gordon B. "Abraham Ribicoff, Statesman or Politician?" Amherst College, 1971.
Sobel, Robert and John Raimo. Biographical Directory of the Governors of the United States, 1789-1978. Westport, Conn.: Meckler Books, 1978 [CSL call number GIS Ref E 176 .B573].
Van Dusen, Albert E. Connecticut. New York: Random House, 1961 [CSL call number HistRef F 94 .V3].
Scope and Content
Gov. Ribicoff's correspondence, subject files, flood of 1955 files, highway safety files, 1958 campaign files, appointment files, speeches, media articles, and press files.
Arrangement
Series 1. Correspondence.
Series 2. Subject Files.
Series 3. Flood of 1955 Files.
Series 4. Highway Safety Files.
Series 5. Campaign Files, 1958.
Series 6. Appointment Files.
Series 7. Speeches.
Series 8. Articles by or about Gov. Ribicoff.
Series 9. Press Files.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Persons:
Ribicoff, Abraham, 1910-1998
Subjects:
Ribicoff, Abraham, 1910-1998 -- Archives; Connecticut. Office of the Governor -- Archives; Connecticut -- History -- Sources; Connecticut -- Politics and government -- 1951- -- Sources; Governors -- Connecticut -- Archives
Document Types:
Correspondence; Records
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - A. D. Higgins Parent-Teacher Association – American Press Institute (Box 591)
  - American Principles Foundation, Inc. – Atmospheric Research, National Institute for (Box 592)
  - Auto registration plates – Bayer, Alwin Christian (Box 593)
  - Bayer, Bill – Biser (Box 594)
  - Bishins – Brandt (Box 595)
  - Branwein – Burndy Library (Box 596)
  - Burnell – Catalfo (Box 597)
  - Catan – City of Hope, Bridgeport Guild (Box 598)
  - City of Light – Congdon (Box 599)
  - Congregation Adath Israel – Coors, Adolph Company (Box 600)
  - Coote – Dalrymple (Box 601)
  - Dalson – Deutsch, Frank (Box 602)
  - Deutsch, J. – Durant (Box 603)
  - Durso – Epps (Box 604)
  - Epstein – Field, Louis N. (Box 605)
  - Field, Newton J. – France (Box 606)
  - Francesconi – General Electric Company (Box 607)
  - General Features Corporation – Goshen, Charles E. (Box 608)
  - Goshen Cove – Hahn (Box 609)
  - Hahr – Harwood (Box 610)
  - Hasak – Holiday time-off (Box 611)
  - Holidays, An Act Concerning Legal – Industrial development (Box 612)
  - Industrial Development Exposition – Jessup, Orson E. (Box 613)
  - Jessup, Theodore C. – Keith, H. (Box 614)
  - Keith, Harold F. – Kregling (Box 615)
  - Kreho – Lee, H. R. (Box 616)
  - Lee, Helen Joy – Loeb, G. M. (Box 617)
  - Loeb, Lawrence Anathan – Malone, Ted (Box 618)
  - Malone, Thomas F. – McCusker (Box 619)
  - McDaniel – Miami, Mayor of (Box 620)
  - Miami Beach Hebrew Academy – Moore, Shirlee (Box 621)
  - Moore, W. Clement – National Academy of Sciences (Box 622)
  - National Health Education Committee, Inc. – New Mexico Teen-Age Traffic Safety Association (Box 623)
  - New Mexico, Village of Espanola – Norwood (Box 624)
  - Nosal Brothers, Inc. – Ozbirn (Box 625)
  - Pabry – Pettengill (Box 626)
  - Pezzenti – Powell, Theodore (Box 627)
  - Powell, Wesley – Quote (Box 628)
  - Rabb – Richardson, Richard C. (Box 629)
  - Richardson, Robert G. – Rourke, Joseph M. (Box 630)
  - Rourke, Margaret D. – Sattler’s (Box 631)
  - Saturday Evening Post – Seventy-Sixth Infantry Division (Box 632)
  - Severance – Skipjack, U. S. S. (Box 633)
  - Skip lines – Sprague, Francis (Box 634)
  - Sprague, Mansfield D. – Stratemeir (Box 635)
  - Stratfield Hotel – Taylor, William P. (Box 636)
  - Taylor, William S. – Toll collectors (Box 637)
  - Toll commutation books – United Advertising Corporation (Box 638)
  - United Air Lines – Vogel, C. A (Box 639)
  - Vogel, Frank N. – Weiner (Box 640)
  - Weingarten – Wilton Historical Society (Box 641)
  - Wilton Playshop – Yale Political Union (Box 642)
  - Yale Scientific – Zylka (Box 643)
- Series 2. Subject Files
  - Accountancy, State Board of, 2 folders (Box 644)
  - Adult Probation, Commission on, 2 folders (Box 644)
  - Aeronautics (Box 644)
  - Aeronautics, Dep[artmen]t of (Box 644)
  - Aging, Governor’s Conference on; Hartford, 1958 May 7; 2 folders (Box 644)
  - Aging, Housing for the (Box 644)
  - Aging, Problems of (Box 644)
  - Aging, White House Conference on, 1961 (Box 644)
  - Agriculture, Conservation and Natural Resources, Dep[artmen]t of, 2 folders (Box 644)
  - Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 644)
  - Agricultural Hall of Fame (Box 644)
  - Agricultural Property, Taxation of (Box 644)
  - Air Pollution (Box 645)
  - Aircraft Trailer Park, East Hartford (Box 645)
  - Alcoholism (Box 645)
  - Alcoholism, Commission on (Box 645)
  - Ambulance and Sunday Auto (Box 645)
  - American School for the Deaf, 2 folders (Box 645)
  - American Weekly Magazine, "Three Day Weekend” (Box 645)
  - Architectural Examining Board, 2 folders (Box 645)
  - Armstrong Rubber Corporation, West Haven, Conn[ecticut] re: Indiana Owned Cars and Trucks (Box 645)
  - Army, U. S., Corps of Engineers, New England Division, 150 Causeway St., 14, Mass[achusetts] (Box 645)
  - Army, U. S., Engineer Div[ision], New England, Waltham, Massachusetts, 2 folders (Box 645)
  - Asiatic Flu Serum (Box 645)
  - Assessments (Box 645)
  - Athletic [Commission] (Box 645)
  - Athletic Commission (Box 645)
  - Auditors of Public Accounts (Box 645)
  - Auditors of Public Accounts – Reports (Box 645)
  - Automobile Insurance Rate Increase (Box 645)
  - Banking Dep[artmen]t (Box 645)
  - Banking [Commissioner] (Box 645)
  - Barbers, Board of Examiners, 2 folders (Box 646)
  - Bazaars and Raffles – Report of John C. Kelley, Commissioner, State Police to Gov[ernor] Ribicoff, 1955-1957 (Box 646)
  - Beach Erosion Background Material (Box 646)
  - Beach Erosion – Beach Town Officials, Legislators, Beach Associations (Box 646)
  - Beach Erosion Conference, Clinton, Conn[ecticut], 1955 April 2 (Box 646)
  - Beach Erosion (Gov[ernor’s] Correspondence) (Box 646)
  - Beach Erosion – Legislation Conference, Gov[ernor]’s Office, 1955 April 6 (Box 646)
  - Beach Erosion – Proposed Legislation (Box 646)
  - Beach Erosion – Reports and Publications (Box 646)
  - Billboards (Box 646)
  - Birdcraft Sanctuary (Box 646)
  - Black Hall River – Old Lyme (Box 646)
  - Blackberry River Watershed (Box 646)
  - Blind, [State] Board of Education of, 4 folders (Box 646)
  - Blind, State Board of Education of the re: Investigation of (Box 646)
  - Blind, State Board of Education of, Removal of Objectionable Material from Vending Stands (Box 646)
  - Booz, Allen and Hamilton Report (Survey of Economic Development) (Box 647)
  - Boundary Lines, State, 1940-1949 (Box 647)
  - Bowles, Chester re: Senate and Congress (Box 647)
  - Bradley Field, Windsor Locks, Conn[ecticut] (Box 647)
  - Brainard Field, Hartford, Conn[ecticut] (Box 647)
  - Bridgeport Armory (Box 647)
  - Bridgeport Charter Bill (Box 647)
  - Bridgeport Juvenile Court (Box 647)
  - Bridgeport Relocation of Route 25, 5 folders (Box 647)
  - Briscoe, Robert (Lord Mayor of Dublin) (Box 647)
  - Bristol, City of (Bills Affecting Same) (Box 647)
  - Bristol Housing (Box 647)
  - Brussels World’s Fair (Box 647)
  - Budget, 2 folders (Box 647)
  - Burke, Albert E. (Comments by) (Box 647)
  - Burr, Ella McManus, Memorial (Box 647)
  - Business Opportunity Exhibit, Dep[artmen]t of Defense, State Armory, Hartford (Box 647)
  - Cancer Society (Box 647)
  - Capital Punishment [Bills Introduced Abolishing, Comments on] (Box 647)
  - Capital Punishment (Folder #2) (Box 648)
  - Capital Punishment (Folder #3) (Box 648)
  - Carpenter Steel of New England, Inc. (Bridgeport, Connecticut) (Box 648)
  - Cedarcrest [Sanatorium] (Box 648)
  - Center for Information on America, Washington, Connecticut, Mr. Townsend Scudder, President (Box 648)
  - Chamber of Commerce Speech (Denver, Colorado, Oct[ober] 6, 1959) (Box 648)
  - Charities, Contributions and Donations (Box 648)
  - Children and Youth, 1960, White House Conference on, March 1960, 3 folders (Box 648)
  - Child Study and Treatment Homes (High Meadows), 2 folders (Box 648)
  - Chiropractic Examiners, 2 folders (Box 648)
  - Chiropody, Board of Examiners in, 2 folders (Box 648)
  - Chronically Ill, Aged Infirm (Box 648)
  - C[ongress] of I[ndustrial] O[rganizations] Union at State Mental Hospitals, Letters rec’d by Gov. Ribicoff (Box 648)
  - Civil Rights Commission (Box 648)
  - Civil Rights – Governor’s Conference, 1960 December 11-12 (Box 648)
    See Press Files, Box 698 for “Civil Rights.” File contains clippings and other material pertaining to the appointment of Attorney Boce Barlow as the first African - American judge in Connecticut history and Ribicoff’s opposition to Arkansas Governor Orville Faubus' states rights stand in the school desegregation controversy in Little Rock.
  - College Heights re: City of New London request that land be transferred to them at the same price paid the Federal Gov[ernmen]t (Box 648)
  - Comic Books [Objectionable Literature] (Box 649)
  - Commerce, Dep[artmen]t of (Box 649)
  - Commitments, Mansfield – Southbury [Training Schools] (Box 649)
  - Comptroller, 2 folders (Box 649)
  - Comptroller, Monthly Statements and Annual Reports, 1956-1960 (Box 649)
  - Congratulations – Letters Received by Gov. Ribicoff re: his office of Governorship [Praise for his job as Governor] (Box 649)
  - Connecticut Colleges and Universities, Presidents and Trustees of (Box 649)
  - Connecticut General Life Insurance Company Property (Box 649)
  - Connecticut General – Symposium, “The New Highways: Challenge to the Metropolitan Region”, 1957 September 9-12; 2 folders (Box 649)
  - Connecticut Government (University of Connecticut Institute of Public Service) (Box 649)
  - Connecticut Marketing Authority, 2 folders (Box 649)
  - Connecticut Medical Examining Board (Box 649)
  - Connecticut Medical Service, Inc. (Box 649)
  - Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (Box 650)
  - Connecticut Reformatory, Cheshire, Conn[ecticut], 2 folders (Box 650)
  - Connecticut Safety Commission, 3 folders (Box 650)
  - Connecticut Safety Commission – Suggestions for Highway Safety – Correspondence (Box 650)
  - Connecticut State Hospital (Box 650)
  - Connecticut State Prison, Board of Pardons, 1955 May-June (Box 650)
  - Connecticut Turnpike, 3 folders (Box 650)
  - Connecticut Turnpike, Hartford Times, 1958 February 28 (Box 650)
  - Connecticut Turnpike, Financing of (Box 650)
  - Consumer Protection, Dep[artmen]t of (Food and Drug Commission) (Box 650)
  - Corporation Laws, Connecticut Commission on the Revision of the (Box 650)
  - Cotter, Bill (Personal) [Special Assistant to the Governor] (Box 650)
  - Council of State Governments, 2 folders (Box 651)
  - Court Reform, 2 folders (Box 651)
  - Court Reform (Judges) (Box 651)
  - Danbury By-Pass (Expressway) (Box 651)
  - Danielson Main Street Railroad – Highway Grade Crossing (Box 651)
  - D.D.T. [Protests against use in Connecticut] (Box 651)
  - Del Gobbo, Joseph, #18043 [Inmate murdered in State Prison] (Box 651)
  - Democratic National Committee, 2 folders (Box 651)
  - Development Commission [State], 4 folders (Box 652)
  - Development Commission – Farmington River Valley Regional Planning Study, 1955-1957 (Box 652)
    See also Box 654.
  - [Development Commission] Luncheon Meeting – Cincinnati, (Acceptances), 1960 May 10 (Box 652)
  - [Development Commission] Luncheon Meeting – Cincinnati, (Regrets), 1960 May 10 (Box 652)
  - [Development Commission –] Missouri (Acceptances), 1960 May 12 (Box 652)
  - [Development Commission –] Missouri (Regrets), 1960 May 12 (Box 652)
  - Development Commission – Naugatuck Valley Region – A Regional Planning Study of Conditions and Prospects, 1955-1957 (Box 652)
  - Divorce (Box 652)
  - [Drought] Clippings and Background (Box 652)
  - [Drought], 1957 (Box 652)
  - Drought, 2 folders (Box 652)
  - Durso, Frank A., Parkway Service Stations (Box 652)
  - Earl, Elliott [Management Analyst and Director, The Institute for Nuclear Serology, Manchester, CT. Letters re use of radiation (Box 652)
  - East Hartford – Rotival and Associates Report – Alternate Highway Proposals: Interstate 491 (Box 653)
  - East Hartford Sand Pit (Box 653)
  - East-West Highway – [The] 341 Trumbull St. Corporation, 2 folders (Box 653)
  - Education (Box 653)
  - Education, State Board of, 3 folders (Box 653)
  - Education, White House Conference on, 3 folders (Box 653)
  - Educational TV (Box 653)
  - Elderly Persons, Commission on Services for, H.B. 1461, 1957 G[eneral] A[ssembly], 3 folders (Box 653)
  - Election, Federal, H. R. 3121 (Box 653)
  - Electric Boat (Division of General Dynamics Corp[oration], Groton, Conn[ecticut] (Box 653)
  - Embalmers and Funeral Directors, Board of Examiners of (Box 653)
  - Employees Merit Award Board (Box 653)
  - Engineers and Land Surveyors (Box 653)
  - Engineers and Land Surveyors, Board of Registration for (Box 653)
  - Epilepsy, 2 folders (Box 653)
  - Erosion Conf[erence], Clinton, C[onnecticu]t, 1955 April 12 (Box 654)
    See also “Beach Erosion” folders in Box 646.
  - Exhibits, Capitol Lobby [Industrial Exhibition], 1955 July (Box 654)
  - Ex-Servicemen re: Unemployment Insurance re: H.R. 11630 (Box 654)
  - “Face the Nation,” Governor’s Appearance on, 1960 July 17 (Box 654)
  - Fairfield Reserve Armory (Box 654)
  - Fairfield State Hospital (Box 654)
  - Fairfield State Hospital (Dr. William F. Green, Sup[erintenden]t) re: Dr. Daniel C. Blain’s Committee [Investigation of the Hospital], 1957 September 30 (Box 654)
  - Farmers Loan – Veto Message – House Bill No. 3 (Box 654)
  - Farmington Valley Region – Regional Planning Study by the firm of Adams, Howard and Greely (Box 654)
  - Federal-State Relations (Box 654)
  - Finance and Control, Dep[artmen]t of, 2 folders (Box 654)
  - Firearms Legislation, 1957 (Box 654)
  - Fire Prevention Conference (Box 654)
  - Fisheries and Game, Board of, 2 folders (Box 654)
  - Fisheries and Game, Dep[artmen]t of (Box 654)
  - Fisheries and Game, State Board of re: Complimentary Hunting and Angling Licenses (Box 654)
  - Fisheries & Game, Board of re: Acquiring public access points (Box 654)
  - Fisheries & Game, Board of re: Complimentary Hunting and (Box 654)
  - Fishing Licenses (Box 654)
  - Flag Manufacturers (Box 654)
  - [Flood of 1955]
    See Boxes 682-686 for files pertaining to the flood and aftermath.
  - Forfeited Rights, Commission on, 2 folders (Box 655)
  - Free Care at State Institutions (Box 655)
  - Frozen Food Code (Box 655)
  - Fuel Oil Strike [Estimate of impact of New York City tugboat strike on availability of fuel oil] (Box 655)
  - Furnace Brook – Middle River Watershed (Box 655)
  - Gambling (Box 655)
  - Gambling, Veto of S.S.B. 121 of Nov[ember] 1955. Special Session: Correspondence (Box 655)
  - Gambling Letters Urging Veto A – B (Box 655)
  - Gambling Letters Urging Veto B – C (Box 655)
  - Gambling Letters Urging Veto D – F (Box 655)
  - Gambling Letters Urging Veto G – H (Box 655)
  - Gambling Letters Urging Veto L – M (Box 655)
  - Gambling Letters Urging Veto N – Q (Box 655)
  - Gambling Letters Urging Veto R – S (Box 655)
  - Gambling Letters Urging Veto W – Z (Box 655)
  - General Assembly – Miscellaneous, 1957 (Box 655)
  - General Assembly, 1957 (Box 655)
  - General Assembly – Transmittal letters [re: bills] [carbon copies], 1959 (Box 655)
  - General Assembly – Accelerated Highway Program Sp[ecial] Sess[ion], 1958 March (Box 656)
  - General Assembly Special Session on Unemployment (Box 656)
  - General Assembly Unemployment Statistics (Box 656)
  - Geological and Natural History Survey, 2 folders (Box 656)
  - Governors’ Conference, 1958 (Box 656)
  - Governors’ Conference– Meeting, 1958 (Box 656)
  - Governors’ Conference, 1959-1960 (Box 656)
  - Governors’ Conference, 1960 (Box 656)
  - Governors’ Conference, Committee on Highway Safety (Box 656)
  - Greater Hartford Bridge Authority, 2 folders (Box 656)
  - Greater Hartford Bridges – Tolls (Box 656)
  - Greenwich–Killingly Expressway (Box 656)
  - Greenwich–Killingly Thruway (Box 656)
  - Greenwich-Killingly [Expressway] – Darien (Box 657)
  - Greenwich-Killingly [Expressway] – Stratford (Box 657)
  - Greenwich Water Company (Box 657)
  - Gubernatorial Messages – Special (Box 657)
  - Gubernatorial Nominations (Box 657)
  - Guideposts, “How To Prevent Your Own Murder,” by Governor Ribicoff (Box 657)
  - Guidepost Article by Governor Ribicoff – Correspondence received (Box 657)
  - Hartford Research Facilities (Box 657)
  - Healing Arts, State Board of (Box 657)
  - Health (Box 657)
  - Health, State Dep[artmen]t of, 3 folders (Box 657)
  - Higher Education, 2 folders (Box 657)
  - Higher Education, N[ew] E[ngland] Board of, 2 folders (Box 657)
  - Highway (Box 657)
  - Highway Aid Bill (H. R. 8836) (Fallon Bill) (Box 657)
  - Highways – Senator Albert Gore’s Federal Aid Highway Bill, 1958 (Box 657)
  - Highway Department, 8 folders (Box 658)
  - Highway Finance Advisory Committee (Box 658)
  - Highway Financing Study Commission (Box 658)
  - Highway Safety, 6 folders (Box 658)
  - Highway Safety, 11 folders (Box 659)
  - Highway Safety, 3 folders (Box 660)
  - Highway Safety Conference (Governor Ribicoff’s Office), 1959 June 30 (Box 660)
  - Highway Safety Conference (August 12, 1960) [Hall of the House] (Box 660)
  - Highway Safety – Detroit Conference (Box 660)
  - Highway Safety – Foreign Countries – Correspondence – Gov. Ribicoff rec[eive]d (Box 660)
  - [Highway Safety] “No License to Kill” presented on the ALCOA HOUR TV – Sunday Evening, 9 – 10PM, 1957 February 3 (Box 660)
  - Highway Safety – “No License to Kill”- ALCOA HOUR – NBC TV (Box 660)
  - Highway Safety – North School, Thompsonville, Conn[ecticut] (Box 660)
  - Highway Safety – Detroit Conference re: Automobile [Manufacturers] [Governors’ Conference Special Committee on Highway Safety], 1958 April (Box 660)
  - [See listing for boxes 687 - 689 for additional files re: Highway Safety.]
  - Highway Toll Collections – Clay Proposal (Box 660)
  - Hoffman, Frank (Box 660)
  - Homeopathic Medical Examining Board, 2 folders (Box 660)
  - Hop Brook Dam (Box 660)
  - Horse Guard (Governor’s) (Box 660)
  - Housatonic Regional High School – Biology Course – Two Week Unit on Human Reproduction [State Police Surveillance] (Box 660)
  - Housatonic River (Box 660)
  - Housing (Box 660)
  - Housing and Home Finance Authority (Box 660)
  - Housing, Temporary State Comm[ission] to Make Studies of and Recommendations for (Box 660)
  - Humane and Welfare Building Program Commission (R. I. Longley, Chairman) (Box 660)
  - Hypertrichologists, Board of Examiners of (Box 660)
  - Inaugural Message of Gov[ernor] Ribicoff, [requests for copies], 1959 January 7 (Box 661)
  - Inauguration (Governor Ribicoff), 1959 (Box 661)
  - Industrial and Development Problems, Permanent Regional Committee on (Box 661)